Guide to the Mario and Ruth Chamlee Collection
Stanford Archive of Recorded Sound
- Recordings
  - Various songs by Ruth Chamlee., 1 sound disc: 33 1/3 rpm, acetate; 12 in. (Box 16, Folder 282)
    Audio Arts Inc. Hollywood.
  - Musical News Reel, July 30, 1935. Part I, 1 sound disc: 33 1/3 rpm, acetate; 12 in. (Box 16, Folder 285)
    Interview with Ruth Adams, Nona Clark and Ruth Miller Chamlee.
    Advertisers' Recording Service, Inc.
  - Madame Chamlee Dec. 17, 1937, 1 sound disc: 78 rpm, acetate; 12 in. (Box 16, Folder 283)
    KMPC. Side 1: Herbert, Victor, 1859-1924. Naughty Marietta. Ah! sweet mystery of life Side 2: First singing lesson.
    Associated Cinema Studios. Hollywood.
  - Ruth Miller Chamlee. Feb. 16, 1938, 1 sound disc: 78 rpm, acetate; 12 in. (Box 16, Folder 284)
    KMPC. Side 1: Manelli, Stefano M. Devozione alla Madonna. Side 2: Lehár, Franz, 1870-1948. Lustige Witwe. Es lebt' eine Vilja Vilja.
    Radio Recorders Inc. Hollywood.
  - Union Oil (Radio program) Apr. 29, 1940, 1 sound disc: 78 rpm, mono., acetate; 12 in. (Box 16, Folder 270)
    Side I: Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Rigoletto. Donna è mobile -- private informal recording, mainly talking rpm change to 33 1/3. Disc inscribed with "Archie pants off or see what I mean"Side 2: Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Rigoletto. Quartetto -- change to 33 1/3 private informal recording, mainly talking.
  - Love's old song, 1 sound disc: 78 rpm, mono., shellac; 10 in. (Box 16, Folder 287)
  - Tony &Gus (Radio program; WJZ)Oct. 6, 1935, sound disc: 78 rpm, aluminum; 12 in. (Box 16, Folder 223)
  - Tony &Gus (Radio program; WJZ)Oct. 6, 1935, sound disc: 78 rpm, aluminum; 12 in. (Box 16, Folder 224)
  - Tony &Gus (Radio program; WJZ)Oct. 6, 1935, sound disc: 78 rpm, aluminum; 12 in. (Box 16, Folder 225)
  - Tony &Gus (Radio program; WJZ)Oct. 13, 1935, sound disc: 78 rpm, aluminum; 12 in. (Box 16, Folder 226)
  - Tony &Gus (Radio program; WJZ)Oct. 13, 1935, sound disc: 78 rpm, aluminum; 12 in. (Box 16, Folder 227)
  - Tony &Gus (Radio program; WJZ)Oct. 13, 1935, sound disc: 78 rpm, aluminum; 12 in. (Box 16, Folder 228)
  - Tony &Gus (Radio program; WJZ)Oct. 13, 1935, sound disc: 78 rpm, aluminum; 12 in. (Box 16, Folder 229)
  - Tony &Gus (Radio program; WJZ)Oct. 20, 1935, sound disc: 78 rpm, aluminum; 12 in. (Box 16, Folder 230)
  - Tony &Gus (Radio program; WJZ)Oct. 20, 1935, sound disc: 78 rpm, aluminum; 12 in. (Box 16, Folder 231)
  - Tony &Gus (Radio program; WJZ)Oct. 20, 1935, sound disc: 78 rpm, aluminum; 12 in. (Box 16, Folder 232)
  - Tony &Gus (Radio program; WJZ)Oct. 20, 1935, sound disc: 78 rpm, aluminum; 12 in. (Box 16, Folder 233)
  - Atwater Kent (Radio program; WABC) Oct. 29, 1934, sound disc: 78 rpm, aluminum; 12 in. (Box 16, Folder 234)
  - Atwater Kent (Radio program; WABC) Oct. 29, 1934, sound disc: 78 rpm, aluminum; 12 in. (Box 16, Folder 235)
  - Atwater Kent (Radio program; WABC) Oct. 29, 1934, sound disc: 78 rpm, aluminum; 12 in. (Box 16, Folder 236)
  - Radio City Party (Radio program; WJZ) Dec. 22, 1934, sound disc: 78 rpm, aluminum; 12 in. (Box 16, Folder 237)
  - Show Boat (Radio program; WEAF) Apr. 18, 1935, sound disc: 78 rpm, aluminum; 12 in. (Box 16, Folder 238)
  - Show Boat (Radio program; WEAF) Apr. 18, 1935, sound disc: 78 rpm, aluminum; 12 in. (Box 16, Folder 239)
  - Swift (Radio program; WEAF) Feb. 10, 1935, sound disc: 78 rpm, aluminum; 12 in. (Box 16, Folder 240)
  - Swift (Radio program; WEAF) Feb. 10, 1935, sound disc: 78 rpm, aluminum; 12 in. (Box 16, Folder 241)
  - Swift (Radio program; WEAF) Feb. 17, 1935, sound disc: 78 rpm, aluminum; 12 in. (Box 16, Folder 242)
  - Swift (Radio program; WEAF) Feb. 17, 1935, sound disc: 78 rpm, aluminum; 12 in. (Box 16, Folder 243)
  - Swift (Radio program; WEAF) Feb. 17, 1935, sound disc: 78 rpm, aluminum; 12 in. (Box 16, Folder 244)
  - Swift (Radio program; WEAF) Feb. 24, 1935, sound disc: 78 rpm, aluminum; 12 in. (Box 16, Folder 245)
  - Swift (Radio program; WEAF) Feb. 24, 1935, sound disc: 78 rpm, aluminum; 12 in. (Box 16, Folder 246)
  - Swift (Radio program; WEAF) Feb. 24, 1935, sound disc: 78 rpm, aluminum; 12 in. (Box 16, Folder 247)
  - Swift (Radio program; WEAF) Mar. 3, 1935, sound disc: 78 rpm, aluminum; 12 in. (Box 16, Folder 248)
  - Swift (Radio program; WEAF) Mar. 3, 1935, sound disc: 78 rpm, aluminum; 12 in. (Box 16, Folder 249)
  - Swift (Radio program; WEAF) Mar. 3, 1935, sound disc: 78 rpm, aluminum; 12 in. (Box 16, Folder 250)
  - Swift (Radio program; WEAF) Mar. 10, 1935, sound disc: 78 rpm, aluminum; 12 in. (Box 16, Folder 251)
  - Swift (Radio program; WEAF) Mar. 10, 1935, sound disc: 78 rpm, aluminum; 12 in. (Box 16, Folder 252)
  - Swift (Radio program; WEAF) Mar. 10, 1935, sound disc: 78 rpm, aluminum; 12 in. (Box 16, Folder 253)
  - Swift (Radio program; WEAF) Mar. 17, 1935, sound disc: 78 rpm, aluminum; 12 in. (Box 16, Folder 254)
  - Swift (Radio program; WEAF) Mar. 17, 1935, sound disc: 78 rpm, aluminum; 12 in. (Box 16, Folder 255)
  - Swift (Radio program; WEAF) Mar. 17, 1935, sound disc: 78 rpm, aluminum; 12 in. (Box 16, Folder 256)
  - Swift (Radio program; WEAF) Mar. 24, 1935, sound disc: 78 rpm, aluminum; 12 in. (Box 16, Folder 257)
  - Swift (Radio program; WEAF) Mar. 24, 1935, sound disc: 78 rpm, aluminum; 12 in. (Box 16, Folder 258)
  - Swift (Radio program; WEAF) Mar. 24, 1935, sound disc: 78 rpm, aluminum; 12 in. (Box 16, Folder 259)
  - Swift (Radio program; WEAF) Mar. 31, 1935, sound disc: 78 rpm, aluminum; 12 in. (Box 16, Folder 260)
  - Swift (Radio program; WEAF) Mar. 31, 1935, sound disc: 78 rpm, aluminum; 12 in. (Box 16, Folder 261)
  - Swift (Radio program; WEAF) Apr. 7, 1935, sound disc: 78 rpm, aluminum; 12 in. (Box 16, Folder 262)
  - Swift (Radio program; WEAF) Apr. 7, 1935, sound disc: 78 rpm, aluminum; 12 in. (Box 16, Folder 263)
  - Swift (Radio program; WEAF) Apr. 7, 1935, sound disc: 78 rpm, aluminum; 12 in. (Box 16, Folder 264)
  - Swift (Radio program; WEAF) Apr. 14, 1935, sound disc: 78 rpm, aluminum; 12 in. (Box 16, Folder 265)
  - Swift (Radio program; WEAF) Apr. 14, 1935, sound disc: 78 rpm, aluminum; 12 in. (Box 16, Folder 266)
  - Swift (Radio program; WEAF) Apr. 14, 1935, sound disc: 78 rpm, aluminum; 12 in. (Box 16, Folder 267)
  - Golden age of opera. Smetana, Bedrich, 1824-1884. Prodaná nevesta. Part I, 1 sound disc: 33 1/3 rpm, mono., 12 in. (Box 16, Folder 273)
  - Golden age of opera. Smetana, Bedrich, 1824-1884. Prodaná nevesta. Part II, 1 sound disc: 33 1/3 rpm, mono., 12 in. (Box 16, Folder 274)
  - Golden age of opera. Smetana, Bedrich, 1824-1884. Prodaná nevesta. Part II, 1 sound disc: 33 1/3 rpm, mono., 12 in. (Box 16, Folder 275)
  - Golden age of opera. Smetana, Bedrich, 1824-1884. Prodaná nevesta. Part II, 1 sound disc: 33 1/3 rpm, mono., 12 in. (Box 16, Folder 276)
  - Musical News Reel, July 30, 1935. Part II, 1 sound disc: 33 1/3 rpm, acetate; 12 in. (Box 16, Folder 286)
- Oversize materials
  - Scrapbook, 16" x 11.5" beige, hard covers (Box 18, Folder 16)
    First entry: The Musical Observer cover with Chamlee's portrait. First date, Nov.22, 1925. Content of complete scrapbook available on microfilm. Scrapbook in very delicate state, should not be handled.
  - Scrapbook, 16" x 10.5" brown cardboard covers. With title "The Ideal Scrap Book" (Box 18, Folder 17)
    First entry: The Musical Observer cover with Chamlee's portrait. First date, Nov.22, 1925. Content of complete scrapbook available on microfilm. Scrapbook in very delicate state, should not be handled. Annotation on spine: "Clippings, S.F.1920; Met 1920; Damrosch; S.F.1921; S.F.1922; Manon 1922; Ravinia 1921 Lucia, Tosca.
  - Scrapbook, 16" x 11.5" Black covers with title "Scrap Book." gathering: black string. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    First page handwritten list of performances with dates. Mario's writing on subsequent page: Season 25-26.
  - Scrapbook, 16" x 11.5" Black covers, no title. Gathering: black string. (Box 8, Folder 4)
    First page: The Chicago Evening Post. August 30, 1927. Stage News and Music. "Mario Chamlee is regarded as a Great Artist"
  - Scrapbook, 16" x 17.5" Black covers, no title. Gathering: black string. (Box 8, Folder 6)
    First page: San Francisco Chronicle. September 27, 1931. Gorgeous Grand Opera Marouf by Rabaud.
  - Scrapbook, 16" x 11.5" Black covers with title "The Ideal Scrap Book." Gathering: black shoe lace. (Box 8, Folder 8)
    First page: Musical Courier Weekly Review of the World's Music with photo of Mario Chamlee as Caponasacchi. Opera by Richard Hageman. First appearance of a date: Aug. 25, 1936.
  - Scrapbook, 24.5"x18.25" brown, beige, yellow and green cardboard covers with geometric patterns. (Box 17, Folder 15)
    First entry "Marouf revived at Metropolitan" June 1937. Content of complete scrapbook available on microfilm. Scrapbook in very delicate state, should not be handled.